>> Brian Holt: 我需要你做的最基本的关键
&gt;&gt; Brian Holt: An absolutely fundamental
key thing that I need you to
现在真正了解的是钩子是永远不会进入的
really understand right now with hooks is
they never go inside of if statements,
他们从不进去做循环之类的事
and they never go inside for
loops or anything like that.
为甚么呢 ? 所以我不能说
Why?
So I can't say like,
如果有什么我做不到的
if (something), I can't do this.
这事没问题千万别这样
This is not okay, never do this.
挂钩工作的方式是
The way that hooks work is,
基本上他们都在跟踪你在制造钩子的顺序
basically, they're keeping track of
the order that you're creating hooks.
所以如果我有另一个钩子，比如比如说
So if I have another hook underneath this,
like for example, like for
动物和 setAnimal
the animal, and setAnimal.
我们会让这只狗或类似的东西
And we'll make this dog or
something like that.
他们跟踪每个个体状态的方式是
The way that they're keeping track
of each individual piece of state is
他们在跟踪你把这些东西叫的顺序对吧
they're keeping track of the order that
you're calling these things in, right?
所以如果我把这些事情说不出来或者如果我有一个声明的话
So if I call these things out of order or
if I have an if statement, and then,
让我们想象吧 [ INAUDIBLE]
let's just imagine [INAUDIBLE],
如果情况 >> Brian Holt: 如果为 true
if something
&gt;&gt; Brian Holt: If this is true
第一次呼叫和第二次通话是假的，这将是第一件事，
on the first call and false in the second
call, this will be the first thing called,
这意味着这将会得到地点而不是动物
which means that this is going to
get location instead of animal,
这会把一切都搞砸了
which is going to mess up everything.
所以就算你无视国家的情况
So even if you're ignoring
what is in useState,
您仍必须在 if 语句之外调用 useState ( 在 for 循环之外 ) 。
you still have to call useState outside of
the if statement, outside of a for loop.
所以我要向你介绍一个 EL Synch 规则
So I'm actually gonna introduce
you to an EL Synch rule
想让你这么做
that want to make you do that.
但我想强调的是你不能
But I just want to very much underscore
the fact that you cannot put in
一个 if 语句，您不能将其放入 for 循环或
an if statement and
you cannot put in a for loop or
任何一种条件或不可预测的逻辑
really any sort of conditional or
unpredictable logic.
>> Brian Holt: 不可避免地，此时的某个人将会向我提问，但
&gt;&gt; Brian Holt: Inevitably, someone at this
point in time is going to ask me like, but
如果我仔细地说它是按顺序来的
what if I'm very careful that
it's called in the same order?
别这样我就会找到你然后我就会羞辱你
Just don't, I will find you and
then I will shame you.
开玩笑的我不知道但求你别这样
[LAUGH] Just kidding,
I don't know, but please don't.
它其实是在码头上强调的，所以它就像从来没有做过一样。
It's actually underscored in the docs, so
it's just something like just never do it.
总是能确保他们在外面
Always make sure that
they're outside of that.
>> Brian Holt: 这适用于所有挂钩，而不仅仅是使用状态，
&gt;&gt; Brian Holt: And this applies
to all hooks, not just useState,
所有钩子都是一般的
all hooks in general.
确保您始终在使用某些内容，对吗 ?
Make sure you are always
using use something, right?
如果你要用这个公约
That's a convention that React,
if you use this convention,
然后 ES 可以帮你执行一些规则
then the ES can help you
enforce some of these rules,